Campbell, Donald A.; Papers apap235
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Donald A. Campbell Papers
1946-1968
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
apap235
2.0 cubic ft.
This collection contains bills, correspondence, supplemental materials, and committee papers from Donald A. Campbell's tenure as a New York State Assemblyman from 1951-1968.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
Donald Campbell initially donated his papers to Syracuse Unviersity in 1968-1969. The papers were transferred to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives in 2006.
Biographical History
Donald Campbell was born in Amsterdam, NY, on August 2, 1922 and died November 8, 1992. He attended Columbia University, served in World War II and attained a commission as a Lieutenant. He then studied law at Albany Law School and graduated in 1948. Campbell was admitted to the Bar Association in the same year. He practiced law before being elected to public office in November 1950.
A Republican and Amsterdam resident, Mr. Campbell served in the New York State Assembly from 1951-1968 where he represented Montgomery County (1951-1965) and, following redistricting, the 123rd District (1966) and the 104th District (1967-1968). He was clerk of the New York State Assembly from 1969-1973 and continued to practice law after leaving office.
He was survived by his wife Phyllis (Topping) Campbell, a son James D. and daughters Patricia and Nancy Campbell.
Scope and Contents
This collection features legislation sponsored by Assemblyman Donald A. Campbell and supplemental correspondence and memorandums. It also includes the official papers of Assemblyman Campbell while a member of The Committee on Economic Expansion for the State of New York.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized alphabetically. There are no series.
Politics and Politicians; New York (State)--Politics and government; Bills (legislative records); Correspondence; Campbell, Donald A., 1922-1992; New York (State)--Legislature--Assembly
- 1951 Bills (Box 1 (Donald A. Campbell Papers), Folder 1)
- 1952 Bills, 1951-1952; Undated (Box 1 (Donald A. Campbell Papers), Folder 2)
- 1953 Bills, 1952-1953; Undated (Box 1 (Donald A. Campbell Papers), Folder 3)
- 1954 Bills, Undated (Box 1 (Donald A. Campbell Papers), Folder 4)
- 1955 Bills, 1954-1955; Undated (Box 1 (Donald A. Campbell Papers), Folder 5)
- 1956 Bills (1 of 2), 1953-1956; Undated (Box 1 (Donald A. Campbell Papers), Folder 6)
- 1956 Bills (2 of 2), 1953-1956; Undated (Box 1 (Donald A. Campbell Papers), Folder 7)
- 1957 Bills, 1954-1957; Undated (Box 1 (Donald A. Campbell Papers), Folder 8)
- 1958 Bills (1 of 2), 1957-1959; Undated (Box 1 (Donald A. Campbell Papers), Folder 9)
- 1958 Bills (2 of 2), 1957-1959; Undated (Box 1 (Donald A. Campbell Papers), Folder 10)
- 1959 Bills (1 of 2), 1946; 1954; 1958-1959; Undated (Box 1 (Donald A. Campbell Papers), Folder 11)
- 1959 Bills (2 of 2), 1946; 1954; 1958-1959; Undated (Box 1 (Donald A. Campbell Papers), Folder 12)
- 1960 Bills (1 of 3), 1948-1949; 1954; 1957-1960; Undated (Box 1 (Donald A. Campbell Papers), Folder 13)
- 1960 Bills (2 of 3), 1948-1949; 1954; 1957-1960; Undated (Box 1 (Donald A. Campbell Papers), Folder 14)
- 1960 Bills (3 of 3), 1948-1949; 1954; 1957-1960; Undated (Box 1 (Donald A. Campbell Papers), Folder 15)
- 1961 Bills (1 of 2), 1960-1961; Undated (Box 2 (Donald A. Campbell Papers), Folder 1)
- 1961 Bills (2 of 2), 1960-1961; Undated (Box 2 (Donald A. Campbell Papers), Folder 2)
- 1962 Bills, 1961-1962; Undated (Box 2 (Donald A. Campbell Papers), Folder 3)
- 1963 Bills (1 of 2), 1961-1963; Undated (Box 2 (Donald A. Campbell Papers), Folder 4)
- 1963 Bills (2 of 2), 1961-1963; Undated (Box 2 (Donald A. Campbell Papers), Folder 5)
- 1964 Bills (1 of 2), 1963-1965; Undated (Box 2 (Donald A. Campbell Papers), Folder 6)
- 1964 Bills (2 of 2), 1963-1965; Undated (Box 2 (Donald A. Campbell Papers), Folder 7)
- 1965 Bills, 1964-1965; Undated (Box 2 (Donald A. Campbell Papers), Folder 8)
- 1966 Bills, 1965-1966; Undated (Box 2 (Donald A. Campbell Papers), Folder 9)
- 1967 Bills, 1966-1967; Undated (Box 2 (Donald A. Campbell Papers), Folder 10)
- 1968 Bills (1 of 2), 1967-1968; Undated (Box 2 (Donald A. Campbell Papers), Folder 11)
- 1968 Bills (2 of 2), 1967-1968; Undated (Box 2 (Donald A. Campbell Papers), Folder 12)
- Committee Papers, 1955; 1959-1961; Undated (Box 2 (Donald A. Campbell Papers), Folder 13)